Seven stories from the heart of the Halo universe.
Halo Legends is a animation, war, action film directed by Hiroshi Yamazaki.
The universe of the Halo video game series is expanded in seven short
animated films from Japan's greatest anime directors and studios.
Female Soldier ("Prototype") / Kelly ("The Package"), played by Luci Christian.
Master Chief, played by David Wald.
Spartan ("The Babysitter"), played by Emily Neves.
Cortana / Dr. Halsey, played by Shelley Calene-Black.
Haka (segment "The Duel"), played by Jessie James Grelle.
Sister (segment "Odd One Out"), played by Brittney Karbowski.
Halo Legends (ヘーローレジェンズ Hērō rejenzu) is a 2010 adult animated military
science fiction anthology film produced by 343 Industries.
The anime compiles seven animated short films, detailing the backstory of the Halo universe, in
addition to providing side stories that expand the universe and tie into the film series.
Following the same pattern that other films such as The Animatrix and Batman: Gotham Knight used, the animated movies were created by six
Japanese anime production houses: Bee Train, Bones, Casio Entertainment, Production I.G., Studio 4°C, and Toei Animation.
Shinji Aramaki, creator and director of Appleseed and Appleseed Ex
Machina, serves as the project's creative advisor.
Warner Bros.
released Legends on DVD and Blu-ray Disc on February 16, 2010.
The idea for an anime compilation existed for years
before there was momentum for the project.
343 creative director Frank O'Connor produced story outlines or finished
scripts that the production houses animated in a variety of styles.
The film explores themes of anthology, based on video game, anime.
The tone is thought_provoking.